A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1969-1974
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1969-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-f
4000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Library acquired these papers from James J. Kilpatrick on 20 Feb 1975.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists chiefly of correspondence in response to Kilpatrick's column and appearances on "Agronsky and Company." Topics cover major issues of 1974, including abortion, amnesty, communism and Alexsandr Solzhenitsyn, conservation, strict interpretation of the constitution, education, energy, E.R.A., a variety of foreign affairs and domestic political issues, law, medical care, the Panama Canal, freedom and abuse of the press, racial issues, particularly busing and affirmative action, and especially Watergate, President Nixon, and impeachment.Also included is correspondence from Colgate Darden and Barry Goldwater. Kilpatrick's speeches, 1969-73, and his broadcasts for Spectrum and WTOP commentaries discuss the same issues.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1974
  - Abortion (Box 1)
  - Agronsky and Company (Box 1)
  - Airships (Box 1)
  - Amnesty (Box 1)
  - Automobiles (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial (Box 1)
  - Calley, William (Box 1)
  - Censorship (Box 1)
  - Communism (Box 1)
  - Conservatism (Box 2)
  - Conservatism: Political Philosophy, General, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Consumerism (Box 3)
  - Credit Cards (Box 3)
  - Education, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Energy (Box 3)
  - Environment (Box 4)
  - Equal Rights (Box 4)
  - Federal Pay Raise (Box 4)
  - Flouridation (Box 4)
  - Food and Famine (Box 4)
  - Ford, Gerald (Box 4)
  - Foreign Affairs, Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Box 4)
  - Income Tax (Box 4)
  - Inflation (Box 4)
  - Jackson, Henry (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, Edward (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Box 5)
  - Labor (Box 5)
  - Law (Box 5)
  - Marijuana (Box 5)
  - Legal Aids (Box 5)
  - McCarthy, Eugene (Box 5)
  - Medical Care (Box 5)
  - Panama Canal (Box 6)
  - Pitts-Lee (Box 6)
  - Poetry (Box 6)
  - Politics, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Polls (Box 6)
  - Pornography (Box 6)
  - Portugal (Box 6)
  - Press (Box 6)
  - Press, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Race, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Religion (Box 8)
  - Rhodesia (Box 8)
  - Right to Work (Box 8)
  - Social Security (Box 8)
  - Spain (Box 9)
  - Tobacco (Box 9)
  - Transportation (Box 9)
  - Truman (Box 9)
  - Richard M. Nixon and Impeachment, Jan-Mar, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Richard M. Nixon and Impeachment, Apr-Jun, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Richard M. Nixon and Impeachment, Jul-Dec, 4 folders (Box 11)
- Speeches 1969-1973
  - Richmond Chamber of Commerce 23 Jan 1969 (Box 12)
  - National Right to Work Directors 31 Jan 1969 (Box 12)
  - Tennessee Manufacturers Association 14 Mar 1969 (Box 12)
  - American Home Economics Association 24 Jun 1969 (Box 12)
  - Charlotte, N.C., Chamber of Commerce (text missing) 16 Jul 1969 (Box 12)
  - Conservative Awards Dinner, Washington, D.C. 4 Oct 1969 (Box 12)
  - Interview, Attorney General Mitchell 28 Jul 1970 (Box 12)
  - On Agnew and the Press, Austin, Texas 21 Oct 1970 (Box 12)
  - Virginia Press Association 15 Jan 1971 (Box 12)
  - California Chamber of Commerce 21 Jan 1971 (Box 12)
  - Young Americans for Freedom 18 Mar 1971 (Box 12)
  - Notes, Debate Wm. Kunstler, University of Oklahoma 31 Mar 1971 (Box 12)
  - Commencement, Prince Edward Academy 5 Jun 1971 (Box 12)
  - Constitutional Change by Interpretation or Amendment; The Restrictive Constitution 8-9 Jul 1971 (Box 12)
  - Southwide Conference on Elementary Education 16 Jul 1971 (Box 12)
  - Texas Christian University (text missing) 5 Oct 1971 (Box 12)
  - Sigma Delta Chi Convention, Washington, D.C. 12 Nov 1971 (Box 12)
  - Ford Motor Company, Detroit 8 Dec 1971 (Box 12)
  - The Written Word, and Association Papers 1967-1969 (Box 12)
  - The Sensuous Publisher 26 Jan 1973 (Box 12)
  - Testimony on Shield Laws, Senate Subcommittee 20 Feb 1973 (Box 12)
  - Genesee Community College, Flint, Michigan (text missing) 21 Mar 1973 (Box 12)
  - Duke Law Forum, Duke University (text missing) 10 Apr 1973 (Box 12)
  - Associated Clubs, San Antonio, Texas (text missing) 3 May 1973 (Box 12)
  - Natonal Governor's Conference, Lake Tahoe 4 Jun 1973 (Box 12)
  - Virginia State Bar, Fredericksburg, Virginia 15 Jun 1973 (Box 12)
  - I.B.M., Fort St. Lucie, Florida 25 Jun 1973 (Box 12)
  - Notes for Interview, Senator Sam Ervin, Washington 1 Aug 1973 (Box 12)
  - American Bar Association 4 Aug 1973 (Box 12)
  - Pennsylvania Publisher's Association, Poconos (Notes only) 28 Sep 1973 (Box 12)
  - Public Policy Training Institute (Notes only) 30 Oct 1973 (Box 12)
  - Randolph-Macon Woman's College (text missing) 12 Nov 1973 (Box 12)
  - St. Andrew's Society 30 Nov 1973 (Box 13)
  - University of Delaware 3 Dec 1973 (Box 13)
- Radio-TV Transcripts
  - TV-Radio, Spectrum, CBS 1972 (Box 13)
  - CBS Spectrum: Radio and TV Commentaries 1973 (Box 13)
  - WTOP Commentaries 1973 (Box 13)